[Music]
welcome to the busy Center Lounge event
and our session about using of
electronic documents in the busy Center
where my colleagues vmir Magnus together
with me will try to explain what this
core functionality has and how you can
use it
now
agenda even there is only six steps it
can not be short presentation is we want
to show completely functionality here uh
we will start with some basic
introduction and high live architecture
but after that we will go deep down and
we will show uh real demos from setup
through the different scenarios in sales
and purchase processes from Sunshine
scenarios to the real issues in the
process so you will see everything and
we will close this session showing the
list of currently available features and
its road
map so let's
start CTC new acronym and relatively new
term and it stands for continuous
transaction control as a this term is
used to describe mandator real time
invoicing reporting
validation by the authorities and
present a set of digital control
mechanism to import tax collection and
decrease STX frauds this is from
government perspective but for us it is
important as more and more countries are
introducing these
requirements okay as you can see on
these slides there are many aspects
where CZ is presented but we will not
cover all of them today you can see
there is electronic V submission sft and
so on some of them we have their
independent
sessions today we'll be focused on a
different models of electronic invoicing
even we change the name of our model
from eVoice into e documents in the
first release we will be focused on a
invoicing on invoicing primary after
that we will continue with some other
document but for now this is primary
focus on
invoicing um okay we are talking about
electronic invoicing as absolutely new
feature but this is not something
absolutely new in the bus Center we
already had fatura PA in Italy and cfdi
in Mexico even if you look SII in space
this is maybe not electronic invoicing
but architecture is pretty similar this
this is more or less the same model and
then many partners created local
specific electronic invoices Solutions
but what we notice as a problem is that
um having different solutions from
country to Country will make problems to
us to provide solution for all these new
countries and support uh for all of them
for existing and new countries but also
for you as it will be more and more more
complicated and it will move us from the
localization idea at all we wanted to
simplify the system and to make it easy
for support solution was create one core
electronic invoicing or electronic
document system as a global app for all
countries it will not be 100% that means
it will not be fit maybe some file
format some more things are missing but
it will be for all country the same
model on the top of that as some things
will be missed we will add some local
flavors as specific small localizations
or local
apps now why we started to think this
way and when we started to think this
way if you look at this road map what
you can see in April this year we had to
enable new cfdi version in Mexico
version 4 it was not so easy effort it
was complicated only one country but now
we need to add Denmark and Belgium to
the list and now before continue with
some other countries and the expected
road map I need to mention that this
road map is maybe not 100% accurate as
governments are changing their
enforcement date all the time it was
accurate in one moment but maybe some of
these countries will be uh uh move
before or after for a couple of
months now if you see there new
countries are coming with their mandated
invoicing rules France Spain German
other countries as well and there is a
VA is a vat in digital age
directive this is new uh this is new e
uh directive about electronic invoicing
in digital V reporting across the
European Union and it was only about
countries where Microsoft has own
localizations what with other countries
you can find numerous countries with the
forc electronic invoicing and we decide
to make it easier to us
and our localizations but also to make
it much more accessible uh for hundreds
of countries where we have partner based
localizations actually not 100 but more
than 100 countries we have parttime B
localizations in some of these countries
electronic invoic is already there in
some of these count this is expected so
we want to make it easier for all of
them not only for Microsoft but for part
and Bas localizations as
well and even when I made my own
research outside of this enforcements
from govern ments I made this Research
on
Twitter uh X now this is X not anymore
Twitter um on This research only 6% of
187 participants say that they do not
need it they do not need electronic
invoice in the bus Center they said I do
not need or I will develop it by
myself all others that means
94% somehow wanted this solution so we
had to do something and okay if you look
know electronic invoicing now it looks
and easy we have a sender and receiver V
are sender for example we need to send
the electronic invoice to our customer
and okay where is the problem it is on
the first side this is really easy but
this is too easy to be real problem is
that countries have different approach
about electronic invoicing this direct
communication is something more or less
available voluntary basing in some
countries but when they enforce they
want something different but on other
side our idea is having powerful
platform to cover the most of models the
most of different situations if not all
and now let's keep on this the most
easier way no Services specific just
communication between customer and u
customer vendor or us with customer and
our vendors this is something that we
call a two Corner model easily
communication we can create electronic
document file and send via email some
other way this is something what you
already have in the v Central you can
export p format and that's it it can
work but very when it comes to third uh
Three Corner model it will be more
complicated because now we have service
provider we need to keep some specific
format service provider as from us and
we do not need to contact Our receiver
our customer uh directly now we need to
send to some API some different model
communication with service provider our
electronic documents and service
provider we deliver this to our customer
and similar uh when our vendor send C
send invoice to us they will send to C
service provider service provider will
delivery to us this is Three Corner
model in some countries Three Corner
model is okay but they're even more
complicated and this is let's say this
is p model and this
is I think the most uh situation in the
most of countries for Corner model where
sender and receiver do not communicate
even between themsel and even with
service provider now we have sender and
receiver access points they have two
access points so sender receiver and two
of access points are four corners and
because of that this is four cornner
model now we we are sender we will send
electronic invoice to our access point
and validation first validation will be
done there so our access point will
communicate with the receiver access
point and receiver access point will
deliver this invoice to receiver but in
the same way they communicate the uh
government Authority so they will
exchange all necessary information with
them but even in this model imagine
there is even more you're in European
union and you want to communicate with
your customer with your C with your
government you must deliver and now you
have forign a customer and you for
foreign customer you need to report to
your government and that's okay you will
have standard file format and you will
deliver it but you have a really big
customer and you want to be really
polite you you want to make your
customer happy and you want to send them
their own uh electronic invoice F format
this is not something enforced but this
is something where you can increase
quality of your business so you can
without any problem ask okay I want to
create additional file format even
different from what I deliver from my
government and I want to send it to my
uh customer that means it can be really
complicated and this is not only about
documents now I explain only how
documents are traveling but there is
even
more um if you look if start for this
the most complicated um standard type
the four cor model let's look deeper
what we need to provide additionally
this is not only about as I said sending
a electon document there is much more
there is additional messaging system and
okay if it start with bus Central we the
bus Central and we have some external
customer for example this is receiver
Erp on this
chart first you as a sender are Corner
one and your customer is as a receiver
is Corner four
and it is expected uh that we we have or
we should have both of our system uh
electronic document messaging system
inside of Erp Solutions but then moving
forward we have access points at the
corner two and Corner three now let's
look at our system more closely it is
essential to establish this in
communication system with the access
point that means we need to communicate
with access point and what does it mean
initially when we dispatch a document to
the access point it will if you validate
the document and promptly provide
initial confirmation message
or if document is uh correct or not but
this is not everything then access
points communicate between themselves
and now after transmitting our document
through the receiver access point our
customer will receive it initially
further interaction from their
end the customer has the option to
either approve or reject the document in
some some countries there will be maybe
even more options a little bit different
but let's keep it this is the most
common scenario customer can approve or
reject document this message will um
then be provided to us by our access
point once it is received from the
receiver access point consequently we
must Implement an additional aschr
service to handle this messaging in a
later point that means you can see this
is not so easy not so un complicated you
need to deliver document you need to to
receive documents you need to deliver
messages to receive messages this is
much more complicated than what we can
conclude on the first
site and how we decided to make it let's
look in a high level architecture of e
document our idea was to create a
document as an
app but there are many places already
inside the Bas app so we didn't want to
remove them from the uh Bas app to this
new app so some of of these features can
be maybe used from some other reasons in
a base app but maybe even more
important um we didn't want to make this
kind of uh breaking changes as many
partner based electronic invoicing
Solutions are based on these existing
features inside the Bas app this is
communication we got uh with the
partners uh when we started to think
about uh making this feature that means
we adapted some of existing part in a
Bas app but the biggest part of our e
doent core app is an extension and this
is a global extension for all countries
it will be used in a W1 and all country
localizations now for example there is
no standard e doent global Service and
because
of because of that the closest to the
standard can be used in some of third
party access points sometimes you you
want to use because this is comfortable
something you will be enforced by
government because they they need they
they will be they will enforce you to
use only certifi access points so we
will soon provide additional e doent
global app ready to connect with a third
party services this have will be based
on our e doent core that means it will
be on the top of e doent core it will
not be independent app and uh these apps
made by Microsoft should provide minimum
80% of required features maybe even more
but minimum
80% now on the top of uh that Microsoft
will provide specific local
ations um in some countries it can be
only file format but sometimes it can be
in service integration eventually maybe
even new tables and Fields if necessary
it depends from requirement local
requirements and they will not be
limited only on these uh three countries
uh here on this slide this is um it will
be enforced by um specific dates when
country expect to have mandatory
electronic invoic in
country we expect that the same model
will be used by partners and U in the
following period we will provide proper
technical documentation how you can
build your your own localization on top
of our e doent cor
app but there are even more options for
partners partner will be able to add
additional value to our localizations
that means not only in a core app you
can extend even our current
localizations current future
localizations maybe some new features
maybe something related with some
industry specifics
there is no limitations you can extend
as you want but there is also an
opportunity for third party access
points you can see uh um our third party
access point providers not our in
general third third party access point
providers will be able to extend these
features uh of uh of these apps as well
now I'm talking about third party access
points app uh because different access
points Point provides providers have
different set of features and we cannot
and we don't plan to deliver their
features BS Central B Cent handle what
is required by default what is required
to deliver invoicing and other documents
to receive to exchange messages and so
but these access points have their own
businesses and their own features so
they can extend our integration app with
additional features if they like it that
means you can use much more feature
inside the be Central if you decide to
communicate directly with access point
provider but the most important thing is
that all of them will use the same base
model and it will not be complicated to
be used and supported in multiple
environments now my colleague while will
continue with deep dive in architecture
and after that we will show all these
live demos
while so now if you are building your
own e doent application you will start
by subscribing to the boosting routine
uh you will obviously need to implement
some backround background jobs to run
run uh all all your code in in a
background job and you might want to
also Implement a mapping field logic uh
in case when you are exporting and
importing documents you want to map the
field to be more uh to to be more to
follow the standard by by that endpoint
you are integrating
with and
then you want to build some logic that
will export and import a document for
each format you're
using uh and then you want to build an
integration with that endpoint you are
trying to send and import documents
from uh you're not done yet you still
need to build error handling logging
retention policy and finally maybe a
dashboard so your customer can follow
the progress of of sending and receiving
e
doents so what we did is that we did the
heavy lifting we package all of that in
E doent core application and that's a
framework to speed up your productivity
when you are trying to build your own e
doent
application all you need to do basically
we package the we created interface for
creating and importing documents and for
integrating with an endpoint to send and
receive documents all you need to do
from your side is to build an
implementation in your localization
application and that would basically
implement the create and and the
exporting and importing of documents for
each format you're supporting it will
also you'll also need to implement an
interface to integrate with that
endpoint to send and receive documents
you can go to extra mile to build a
setup wizard to automate the the first
step your customer have to do where
basically you collect all the
information to which format they using
which endpoint uh they are integrating
to collecting all the I don't know
username certificates and stuff like
that
now we actually built a demo
localization app to basically demo how
the E doent core would look like from a
customer point of view and we will show
you that
demo and now we will show you a demo of
our uh test localization apps that we
built on top of eent core uh so let's
start with setup the first part that
you're going to do to set this up is to
go to E doent
service and we're going to create a new
one so let's call it Kronos
service and will give it a
description
this to
send and
receive document from test
service and yeah we'll choose document
format so we created a p test format and
also we created a Chronos integration a
test
integration uh you will see there are a
lot of uh fields and properties that you
can play with uh for example we are
supporting patch processing natively uh
so you can check that later we also have
import parameters when you're importing
a documents and then we have mapping uh
when you exporting and importing so just
for for for for the sake of demo we will
show you we will try to basically create
everything that we export and transform
it to be
uppercase uh utilizing the
transformation
rule uh the last thing is that I will
also create the setup uh for service
integration here I can add the endpoint
and uh sending endpoint and receiving
endpoint so now I will get my sending
endpoint link
so we created just like a test service
that we can uh use for for this
uh for this demo and yeah now it's set
up up and ready so the next part is that
I will need to go to
workflow I will create like a new
workflow then I'll show you how you can
do it manually we also have templates
but for the sake of this demo we'll do
it manually so
simple let's call it simple
flow send e
document and make sure to choose the
category as e document and the event
that we created is that when e document
is
created and I will choose a response as
when an e document created we want to
send this e doent using setup and then
right here I'll choose the setup which
is Cronus service that we just created
you can actually send to multiple
service by clicking add more responses
uh but for the sake of the simple demo
let's just into one
service and finally I'll enable this
one now we have one last step in in this
setup which is basically to go to
document sending
profile and I created a default one
earlier on so the only thing I will
choose is that a as electronic document
we will use yeah choose extended eent
service flow and then I will choose the
simple flow that we just created great
now we are ready to send an example e
invoice and my colleague Manus will show
you how you can do
that all right thanks while let's see
how the electronic document solution
Works in this the sales process to
illustrate this I will create and post a
sales invoice for a
customer that has electronic documents
enabled in their document sending
profile so let's just sell one
bicycle post this
invoice and once posted we can actually
go directly to the E doent from the
posted sales invoice page through the
related e doent
action this will open up the E doent
where we will be able to see details
about the sales invoice we just posted
such as posting date The Entity involved
and other important information as well
as a link to the sales inv
itself the next thing you would probably
want to look at is the status of this
electronic document and where it is in
the processing pipeline as we can see
here the electronic document status is
set to process
this gives you a real-time View at where
the document is in the in the pipeline
and if you want a more in-depth view on
a service level you can go to the E
doent service status which will give you
the status of the document for each
service here we can see that we use the
Chronos service to send to and we can
see that the status is set to
send we can even go further in detail in
the locks which will provide a
chronological overview of the events
that this document has been through so
the first thing we will see is that the
document was exported the next thing
that happened was that it was
sent looking at the exported entry we
have the option to actually open the
mapping where we can see that we
uppercased all the fields that was used
in this export it's also possible to
export the file and review it
manually yes so if you're interested in
the communication that happens between
you and the service that you're sending
to you can even go to communication logs
where we will provide information about
the request and response message that
was with that
service and of course this document was
processed successfully but we all know
that sometimes Services might go down
from time to time due to availability or
other problems that might
arise this of course we also handle so
let's see an example where the service
will throw an error and how we deal with
that so we'll just create a new sales
invoice for the same
customer sell another
bike let's
posted and go to the posted sales
invoice where now we should see that the
E
doent has a sending error we can even
see that the document status is error as
well as we provide the error message for
the user such that they can read and
understand what what might be the
problem of course they can also go to
the communication
logs to try and figure out if there is
some problem with the the response or
the
request
in order to come around this we give you
the option to use manual
actions as you can see here we can
actually send the document we can
recreate the document we can cancel or
get approval these are different types
of manual actions that might help you
get out of a situation like this one all
right so let's uh send to this service
that was no longer working that now
should be back online so we just pick
the Chona service
again and now you can actually see that
the electronic document status was
updated to be processed as well as the
status on the specific service was
changed to send meaning we actually
succeeded in in sending and the manual
actions did what it's supposed to do yes
and now that we showed you how sending
documents work my colleague will guide
you through how importing documents work
with our
solution yeah thank you Magnus and hello
to everyone uh now we are switching to
the receiving side and uh before we get
to the process let me just briefly show
you the
setup we have uh a document
service uh
with receiving endpoint which is
basically a service that is sending P
invoices
receiving e documents uh is done uh by a
bad job but uh for the purpose of this
demonstration we are not running uh the
job queue uh automatically we're going
to run it manually so let me just run
the
we got a
success and we got our electronic
documents in the system as you can see
this is a s change scenario we already
um we didn't get any error so we already
created a purchase invoice out of the
document and we can see that uh the item
number
10,000 in Chronos that was sent to
our site is mapped to
uh item number
101 and this is because we have a item
reference for this
item uh going to post the
document and
our e doent is also updated so we now
pointing to the posted purchase
invoice uh what will happen if we get an
error during
import let's just simulate the error
using the same document
but uh removing item
reference I go to item and I remove this
reference
then I'm going to run JQ once again
manually and we got a message that there
is an error by the way this uh this is
only if gu is
allowed now we see the error that uh we
cannot find any item based on what we
received how we can bypass this error we
can go
to map text to account for example and
then we can
specify that item with this text should
go to this account instead of uh being
uh mapped to another
item then we can reprocess it
manually
so the invoice is
created and now we have g account
line there is also a possibility to uh
create Journal lines instead of document
and in order to do so I'm going to
remove uh this
mappin and run job Q once
again
I get the error uh but what can I do
from
here I can
map everything that is coming from this
customer
to be used on this
account
uh and then I can create
Journal so no error here we get a
warning that this document already exist
we can jump to the
journal let's actually already some
lenses in
here and we can post this
journal I might get an error because of
which is document already
exist and now we can post this journal I
only need to update the document number
because it already exist in our
system Journal was successfully posted
and if I go back I can see that eent now
points to GL
entry so that was the overview of the
import part and uh now my colleague
Alexander will continue with details
about features and road
map okay thank you Vladimir and I will
just finish this session uh but before
uh finishing I want to explain few more
important things about available
features what is covered with this
release and what you can expect in the
future okay first to be clear what we
have covered in this release we have uh
from sales perspective about sales
invoices we can create electronic
invoice from sales invoice and from
sales order from purchase side you can
import
um uh your electronic documents to
purchase inv voice and purchase order
but only if you want to create new
purchase order not to update existing
one and even if this is not on a list as
you can see from voler demos you can uh
you can import to journal as well then
about credit memos uh both credit memos
from sales and purchase side they are
covered with this leas and important not
about documents this is configurable you
can configure really on a really good
level and you can extend if you need for
your local
markets uh all messages depends on local
features because they cannot be
introduced uh in a global feature only
basic things are here everything else
will be on a local
level about road map uh this is
continuing improvements uh we don't want
to finish in one releasee electronic
document because this is complex story
and we will continue in next minimum two
releases to deliver uh new features
there what is first I mentioned in the
beginning not in beginning one moment
that we are preparing this third party
access points app it will be already
until the end of this year as a new app
on top of um e doent core and then uh we
will continue with the first the let's
say the biggest uh feature Improvement
updating existing purchase order that
means in a case you already have created
purchase order and now you will get
purchase invoice for just part of this
purchase order and to map it this is
something what we are planning to
deliver as a first uh feature
Improvement then about localizations now
we cannot say exactly which localization
will come first as you could see Denmark
must work from January and um in Belgium
we need to have received documents in in
in January so probably uh we can say
that Denmark and Belgium will come first
but all other countries depends on a
enforcement dates on a local markets
that means when we when we see that this
is mandatory in one country we will
deliver all localizations on a time now
I'm talking about Microsoft based
localizations and if you are asking or
if you ask yourself about access points
if Microsoft will provide access point
or not how it works and you could see
that we are are providing third party
access points communication as well
there is no uh Universal and unique
answer it depends again from country to
Country this is not in a global app this
is something what will come in a
localizations and if uh authorities in
one countries provide us uncer
uncertified uh access point to
communicate with their their service we
will deliver this but if uh authorities
require certified service for example in
um Denmark it is required to access
point be certified service and this is
not something but Microsoft can provide
so we will communicate through third
access points providers you can choose
which um access point provider you want
to use this is on our customers our
partners but we will provide everything
to communicate and to be integrated with
them okay that's everything for today uh
I want to thank uh to say thank you in
my name and the name of my colleagues
and before I close this session I just
want to invite you to to join all
sessions in BC lunch event but
especially these two because they are
connected or interconnected with this
topic first is what is new related with
the new Danish bookkeeping act because
we will talk about electronic invoicing
in Denmark so it will be directly
connected with this session and what is
new legislation localization because it
will be about all features created this
area
and if you need more information about
business cental about our services and
so you can find all important links on
this page if you cannot remember all of
them try to not to forget this one in a
middle AKA MSB this is a place where you
can find all these links on one common
place once more thank you
and I hope this feature will be good for
you